Finding Aid for the George P. Johnson Negro Film Collection LSC.1042
UCLA Library Special Collections
George P. Johnson Negro Film collection
1916-1977
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1042
35.5 Linear Feet (71 boxes)
George Perry Johnson (1885-1977) was a writer, producer, and distributor for the Lincoln Motion Picture Company (1916-23). After the company closed, he established and ran the Pacific Coast News Bureau for the dissemination of Negro news of national importance (1923-27). He started the Negro in film collection about the time he started working for Lincoln. The collection consists of newspaper clippings, photographs, publicity material, posters, correspondence, and business records related to early Black film companies, Black films, films with Black casts, and Black musicians, sports figures and entertainers.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed digital materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
George P. Johnson, purchase and gift, 1968-1971.
Gift of Charles Caballero, 1992.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332203606533
Biography
George Perry Johnson was born in Colorado Springs, Colorado, October 29, 1885; after his graduation from the Hampton Institute, Virginia (1904), he settled in Tulsa, Oklahoma and started the first Negro paper in the territory, The Tulsa Guide (June 9, 1906); moved to Omaha, Nebraska (1913) and was the first Negro employee at the U.S. Post Office in that city; he eventually moved to Los Angeles and continued working for the post office while he worked as a writer, producer, and distributor for the Lincoln Motion Picture Company (1916-23); after the company closed, he established and ran the Pacific Coast News Bureau for the dissemination of Negro news of national importance (1923-27); he started the Negro in film collection about the time he started working for Lincoln; he died October 17, 1977.
Scope and Content
Collection consists primarily of material related to the Lincoln Motion Picture Company, Johnson's brother, Noble Johnson, Oscar Micheaux, and the Oscar Micheaux Film and Book Company. Includes newspaper clippings, photographs, publicity material, posters, correspondence, and business records. Also includes materials related to early Black film companies, Black films, and films with Black casts, and Black musicians, sports figures, and entertainers. Also contains personal papers of George P. Johnson.
Expanded Scope and Content
The George P. Johnson Negro Film Collection was assembled over a period of more than fifty years by one of the industry's pioneer producers and distributors of Black films. It contains newspaper clippings, photographs, publicity materials, posters, and, in some instances, correspondence and business records of early Black film companies. Mr. Johnson often added his own remembered information about films or performers, typing this information on slips of paper or cards.
The collection has its greatest depth in material relating to Mr. Johnson's own Lincoln Motion Picture Company, to Noble Johnson who was George P. Johnson's brother, and to Oscar Micheaux and the Oscar Micheaux Film and Book Company whose moving pictures Johnson distributed. It also has hard-to-find material on Black musicians, sports figures, entertainers, and on Black films and on Black films and film companies and films with Black casts.
The register for the collection is a card file (shelf list) which is divided into two alphabets, one for personal names and one for films and film companies. This brings together films made by the Lincoln Motion Picture Company. All of the films in which Oscar Micheaux appeared are brought together under his name. There is no indication of how much material will be found for an entry. It may be anything from a single clipping to several folders full of material.
Revised October 1995
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Research files (Boxes 1-47).
Newspapers and magazines (Boxes 48-50, 70).
Films and videotape (Boxes 51, 53, 63).
Personal papers, photographs, magazines, books, and files of Lincoln Motion Picture Company (Boxes 51-69).
Posters (Oversize folder 71).
Expanded Organization and Arrangement
The following statement appears at the beginning of each reel of microfilm of the George P. Johnson Collection:
George P. Johnson who started in the motion picture industry in 1961 as General Booking Manager for Lincoln Motion Picture Company, has assembled a collection primarily of ephemeral materials - correspondence, playbills, newspaper clippings, advertisement materials, photographs relating to Blacks in all fields of entertainment, sports and the arts. Its major strength is in the area of motion pictures. It contains records of films made by Blacks, films in which Blacks appeared, films with all Black casts, Black motion picture houses, booking agencies, music publishers, magazines and similar related subjects.
Mr. Johnson's materials revealing the history of the Lincoln Motion Picture Company are the highlight of the collection. Correspondence and other manuscripts focus on the problems, politics, psychological conflicts, deals, business failures, promotional techniques, and financial solicitations of the company and depict how this black enterprise managed to exist from 1916 to 1923. Information concerning the company itself is found throughout the collection, with concentrations of material found under the following headings. (see Index for reel and frame numbers.):
Birth of a Race (film)
Brooks, Clarence
Dudley, S.H.
Film Production Companies
Foster, William
Gant, Harry
Ireland, Thomas D.
Johnson, George
Johnson, Noble
Levy Robert
Lincoln Motion Picture Company
Micheaux, Oscar
Smith, James Rodney
Teycer, B.L.
Turpin, Charles H.
Vann, Robert
Some names and events are not listed separately in the index itself, but are included within certain broad headings listed below. Check this special list of headings for possible leads to additional information on related subjects. Reel and frame numbers are located in the index under the following headings:
Academy Awards
Actors Replaced by Other Actors
Afro-American Film Exhibitors
Black Film Theatres
Black Man in Films
Black Musicians' Union
Casting
Colored Americans War Film
Colored and Indian Film
Colored Champions of Sport
Comedians
Entertainers, Negro
Federal Theatre Project
Film Production Companies
Footlite Magazine
Harlem
Hollywood Maids
Hollywood Productions
Sambo Comedies
Lincoln Motion Picture Company
List of White & Black Companies Producing Black Films
Motion Picture Industry
Moving Picture Film Companies
Moving Picture Film History
Music Score Arrangers, Writers
Negro
Actors
Authors
Book Dealers
Boxers
Comedy Films
History
In Moving Pictures
In Radio
In Television
Newspapers
Theatre
Theatres
Westerns
100 years of Negro Entertainment, an Ebony article.
Outlet - a Western Monthly
Pacific News Bureau
Racism & Entertainment
Theatrical Booking Agencies
Unions
Vaudeville Stars
War Films
Existence and Location of Copies
Digitized materials are available electronically at https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/r9kf9000zz-89112.
Portions of this collection are available on microfilm (12 reels) in UCLA Library Special Collections.
Related Oral History
The following oral history is available through the UCLA Library Center for Oral History Research:
Collector of Negro film history [oral history transcript] / George P. Johnson, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1970. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
General note
* An Asterisk indicates that within these frames one will find biographical information concerning a performer and a list of his or her films. For example, Dorothy Dandridge's main entry is between frame numbers 275-358 *. For additional information concerning her life it would also be worthwhile to check information on each of her films. Information concerning each film is listed under the film's title.
African Americans in motion pictures.; African Americans in the motion picture industry.; Johnson, Noble; Lincoln Motion Picture Company; Micheaux Film Corporation; Micheaux, Oscar; Johnson, George P., 1885-1977
- Research Files
  General note
  These have been microfilmed.
  Further information can be found in the following sections:
  Cambridge, Godfrey
  Footlite Magazine
  Parker, Charlie
  - Reels - Positive Microfilm
    (Microfilm is for boxes 1-47 only of the collection)
    - Abandoned to Boar's Tooth Ceremonial. (Reel 1)
    - Bob Mathias Story to Close Harmony. (Reel 2)
    - Cole, Carol to Davis, Robert. (Reel 3)
    - Davis, Sammy to Four Feathers. (Reel 4)
    - Four for Texas to Hoosman, Alabama. (Reel 5)
    - Horne, Lena to Khartoum. (Reel 6)
    - The Kid from Left Field to Lonesome Road. (Reel 7)
    - Lone Star Motion Picture Producers to Moving Picture History. (Reel 8)
    - Moving Picture Industry to The Nun's Story. (Reel 9)
    - Oceans 11 to Quinn, Carol. (Reel 10)
    - Rachel, Rachel to Still, William Grant. (Reel 11)
    - Stop the World, I Want to Get Off to end. (Reel 12)
  - A
    - Abrams, Dick, Frame(s) 392-562. (Reel 8)
    - Abrams, Ed, Frame(s) 392-562. (Reel 8)
    - Abrams, Richard (Dick)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 2-3. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 294-5, Gunsanlus Mystery. (Reel 5)
    - Absent, Frame(s) 353-363, Rosebud Film Company. (Reel 11)
    - Academy Awards, Frame(s) 4-14. (Reel 1)
    - The Accused
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 15. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 4, Motion Picture Industry. (Reel 9)
    - Actors Replaced by Other Actors, Frame(s) 469. (Reel 5)
    - Adams, Fay, Frame(s) 16, Rhythm & Blues. (Reel 1)
    - Adams, Joe
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 17. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 311-312, Carmen Jones. (Reel 2)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 406-429, Ray Charles. (Reel 2)
    - Adams, Robert, Frame(s) 18. (Reel 1)
    - Adderley, Julian Cannonball, Frame(s) 667, New Face in Hell. (Reel 9)
    - Adderly, Nat, Frame(s) 418, Miles Davis. (Reel 3)
    - Adventure, Frame(s) 19. (Reel 1)
    - Adventures in Paradise, Frame(s) 20, Juano Hernadez. (Reel 1)
    - Adventures of a Young Man, Frame(s) 21, Juano Hernadez. (Reel 1)
    - Adventures of Ali Baba, Frame(s) 22, Greg Morris. (Reel 1)
    - Adventures of Hajai Baba, Frame(s) 23, Nat King Cole. (Reel 1)
    - Adventures of Huckleberry Finn, Frame(s) 24. (Reel 1)
    - Adventures of Mark Twain, Frame(s) 25. (Reel 1)
    - Advise and Consent
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 26. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 159, Merville Brown. (Reel 2)
    - A for Assasin, Frame(s) 28, Raymond St. Jacques. (Reel 1)
    - Affair in Trinidad, Frame(s) 27, Juanita Moore. (Reel 1)
    - Africa Addio, Frame(s) 29. (Reel 1)
    - Africa - Blood & Guts, Frame(s) 570. (Reel 9)
    - Africa - Texas Style, Frame(s) 30. (Reel 1)
    - The African, Frame(s) 31, Early Hyman. (Reel 1)
    - The African Elephant, Frame(s) 542. (Reel 9)
    - African Fury, Frame(s) 32. (Reel 1)
      See also Cry the Beloved Country.
    - African in London, An, Frame(s) 18, Robert Adams. (Reel 1)
    - Afro-American Concert Band, Frame(s) 504,. (Reel 7)
    - Afro-American Film Exhibitors
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 33, Film Productions. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 405, A. Porter Davis. (Reel 3)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 118, Organized. (Reel 8)
    - Aquabello, Francesco, Frame(s) 352, Katherine Dunham. (Reel 4)
    - Aikens, Vanoye, Frame(s) 350, Katherine Dunham. (Reel 4)
    - Ailey, Alvin, Frame(s) 209-218, Claudia McNeil. (Reel 8)
    - Ain't She Sweet, Frame(s) 166-174, Sain Langford. (Reel 7)
    - Ajala, Mashood Olabisi
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 34. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 884, White Witch Doctor. (Reel 12)
    - Aladdin & His Lamp, Frame(s) 35, Madi Comfort. (Reel 1)
    - Alamo, The, Frame(s) 36, Jester Hairston. (Reel 1)
    - Aldridge, Ira
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 37, Negro history, Othello. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 3, Robert Abrams. (Reel 1)
    - Alex in Wonderland, Frame(s) 537, 543. (Reel 9)
    - Alexander, Bill, Frame(s) 38. (Reel 1)
    - Alexander, Chip, Frame(s) 39, Flower Drum Song. (Reel 1)
    - Ali Baba Goes to Town, Frame(s) 40, The Peters Sisters. (Reel 1)
    - Ali, Muhammad
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 121, Jim Brown; 484-491. (Reel 2)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 553-575, James Earl Jones. (Reel 6)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 666-677, Archie Moore. (Reel 8)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 426, Negro Boxers. (Reel 9)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 92, Requiem for a Heavyweight. (Reel 11)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 408, Two for Texas. (Reel 12)
    - Alice Adams, Frame(s) 43, Hattie McDaniels. (Reel 1)
    - Alix, Mae, Frame(s) 145, Photo. (Reel 1)
    - All American, The, Frame(s) 41, Clarence Wilson. (Reel 1)
    - All By Myself, Frame(s) 42, Louise Beavers. (Reel 1)
    - All-American News, Incorporated, Frame(s) 44, Negro Newsreels. (Reel 1)
    - All Brother's were Valiant, Frame(s) 53, Robert Craig. (Reel 1)
    - All Crooked Hearts, Frame(s) 45, William Marshall. (Reel 1)
    - All God's Children, Frame(s) 52, Richard Rust, Hari Rhodes. (Reel 1)
    - All Night Long, Frame(s) 54, Paul Harris, Marti Stevens. (Reel 1)
    - All the Fine Young Cannibals, Frame(s) 55, 56, Pearl Bailey, Louise Beavers. (Reel 1)
    - All Young Men
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 57-61. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 534. (Reel 4)
    - Allen, Anna E., Frame(s) 46, The Harlem Globetrotters. (Reel 1)
    - Allen, Anna Lo, Frame(s) 476-477, Hearts of the Woods. (Reel 5)
    - Allen, Billie, Frame(s) 47, Black Like Me; 644-648, Black Like Me. (Reel 1)
    - Allen, Charles, Frame(s) 405-409, A. Porter Davis. (Reel 3)
    - Allen, Clarice, Frame(s) 385, Death. (Reel 1)
    - Allen, Dick, Frame(s) 48, Vignette Films. (Reel 1)
    - Allen, George H., Frame(s) 33, Afro-American Film Company. (Reel 1)
    - Allen, Shepard, Frame(s) 49-51. (Reel 1)
    - Aloma of the South Seas, Frame(s) 62, Nobel Johnson. (Reel 1)
    - Alston, Barbara, Frame(s) 63-64, Sepia Magazine. (Reel 1)
    - Alston, James, Frame(s) 70, American Black Star Productions. (Reel 1)
    - Alvarez Kelly, Frame(s) 65, Mantan Moorland. (Reel 1)
    - Amateur Daddy, Frame(s) 66, Clarence Wilson. (Reel 1)
    - Ambushers, The, Frame(s) 67, Senta Berger. (Reel 1)
    - Amen Corner, The, Frame(s) 679-686, Beah Richards. (Reel 8)
    - America by Night, Frame(s) 68, Lionel Hampton. (Reel 1)
    - American Hero, An, Frame(s) 69, Medford. (Reel 1)
    - American Black Star Production, Frame(s) 70. (Reel 1)
    - American Motion Picture Company, Frame(s) 71, Organized. (Reel 1)
    - American Negro Public Opinion (ANPO), Frame(s) 270, Mrs. Ruby Dale, Director. (Reel 3)
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 156-495, Louis Armstrong. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 910, William Still Grant. (Reel 11)
    - Amos and Andy
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 72-73, 17, Joe Adams. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 153-155, Roy Glenn; 300-305, Jester Hairston. (Reel 5)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 222, John Lee. (Reel 7)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 23, Amanda Randolph. (Reel 11)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 942-959, Spencer Williams. (Reel 12)
    - Anatomy of a Murder, Frame(s) 74-75, Duke Ellington. (Reel 1)
    - And Now Tomorrow, Frame(s) 115, Ernest Anderson. (Reel 1)
    - Anderson, Allegretti, Frame(s) 76, Georgia Rose; 144-149. (Reel 1)
    - Anderson, Cat William
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 247, Jam session. (Reel 2)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 449-489, Duke Ellington. (Reel 4)
    - Anderson, Mrs. Charles, Frame(s) 262, Robert Levy. (Reel 7)
    - Anderson, Eddie
      See Rochester
    - Anderson, Ernest, Frame(s) 88-89, His films & movie career. (Reel 1)
      Films are listed within these frame numbers.
    - Anderson, Ester, Frame(s) 90. (Reel 1)
    - Anderson, Garland
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 411. (Reel 9)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 256, Pacific Coast News Bureau. (Reel 10)
    - Anderson, Inez, Frame(s) 91, Eagle of the Sea. (Reel 1)
    - Anderson, Ivie
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 92, 97, Her films. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 37, A Day at the Races. (Reel 4)
    - Anderson, Joseph B. Jr. Lt., Frame(s) 110. (Reel 1)
    - Anderson, Marion
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 93-107. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 513, 651. (Reel 4)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 152-154, Lady from Philadelphia. (Reel 7)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 407-417, Negro Authors. (Reel 9)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 25-27, Of Men & Music. (Reel 10)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 909-910, Willam Grant Still. (Reel 11)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 306, Tonight We Sing. (Reel 12)
    - Anderson, Myrtle
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 108. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 253, Green Pastures. (Reel 5)
    - Anderson, William Cat
      See Anderson, Cat
    - Andlauer Productions, Frame(s) 111-114. (Reel 1)
    - Andre, Carole, Frame(s) 398. (Reel 9)
    - Andre, Francoise, Frame(s) 116. (Reel 1)
    - Andrews, Charles, Frame(s) 253, Green Pastures. (Reel 5)
    - Androcles & the Lion, Frame(s) 117-118, Wally Strode. (Reel 1)
    - Angel Levine, Frame(s) 457-529, Harry Belafonte. (Reel 1)
    - Angelo in the Crowd, Frame(s) 119, Angelo Maggio. (Reel 1)
    - Angelou, Maya, Frame(s) 259, Calypso Heat Wave. (Reel 2)
    - Anna Lucasta
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 120-126. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 180, Rosetta La Noire. (Reel 7)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 664-672, Hilda Simms (Theatre) Footlite Magazine. (Reel 11)
    - Annapolis Farewell, Frame(s) 127, Louise Beaver. (Reel 1)
    - Anna's Sin, Frame(s) 128-130. (Reel 1)
    - Another Country, Frame(s) 131. (Reel 1)
    - Another Face, Frame(s) 132, Hattie McDaniels. (Reel 1)
    - ANPO
      See American Negro Public Opinion
    - Anthony, Earl, Frame(s) 409. (Reel 9)
    - Apache, Frame(s) 133, Archie Savage. (Reel 1)
    - Apache, The, Frame(s) 134, Noble Johnson. (Reel 1)
    - Apache Drums, Frame(s) 135, Clarence Muse. (Reel 1)
    - Apartment, The, Frame(s) 136. (Reel 1)
    - Ape's Claw, The, Frame(s) 137. (Reel 1)
    - Apex, The, Frame(s) 629-672. (Reel 4)
    - Apollo Theatre
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 153, Henry Armstrong. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 170, Ralph Cooper. (Reel 3)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 407, Billy Eckstine; 629-672. (Reel 4)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 80, Gang War; 576, Billie Holliday. (Reel 5)
    - Apostle of Freedom, Frame(s) 138, Juano Hernandez. (Reel 1)
    - Appaloosa, Frame(s) 139-140. (Reel 1)
    - Appley, Hilda, Frame(s) 511, Herald Pictures. (Reel 5)
    - Aquarious, Karl, Frame(s) 141. (Reel 1)
    - Arch of Triumph, Frame(s) 142, Hazel Brooks. (Reel 1)
    - Argus Pictures, Frame(s) 236, Double Deal. (Reel 1)
    - Aristo Art Film Corporation, Frame(s) 143. (Reel 1)
    - Aristo Films, Frame(s) 144-149. (Reel 1)
    - Arizonian, The, Frame(s) 150, Willie Best. (Reel 1)
    - Arm of the Law, Frame(s) 151. (Reel 1)
    - Armstrong, Henry
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 85, 87, 153-155. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 624, Keep Punching. (Reel 6)
    - Armstrong, Lil Hardin, Frame(s) 156, 159, Death; 163-167, Louis Armstrong's death; 178, 213-217. (Reel 1)
    - Armstrong, Louis Satchmo
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 156-227; * 495, 556, The Berry Brothers. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 361, Benny Carter; 612, Nat King Cole. (Reel 2)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 373, Billy Daniels. (Reel 3)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 629-672, Footlite Magazine. (Reel 4)
    - Arnau, Brenda, Frame(s) 228. (Reel 1)
    - Arnold, Jeanne
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 229. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 171, The Out-of-Towners. (Reel 10)
    - Arnster, Willie, Frame(s) 230. (Reel 1)
    - Arrington, Roscoe, Frame(s) 231. (Reel 1)
    - Arrivederci, Frame(s) 152. (Reel 1)
    - Arrowsmith, Frame(s) 232-233, Clarence Brooks. (Reel 1)
    - Art of Love, The, Frame(s) 234. (Reel 1)
    - As the World Rolls On, Frame(s) 111-114. (Reel 1)
    - ASCAP
      See American Society of Composers, Authors & Publishers
    - Assault on a Queen, Frame(s) 235. (Reel 1)
    - Assignment, Frame(s) 237, Eric Portman. (Reel 1)
    - Associated Negro Picture Distributers, Frame(s) 238-239, Negro Westerns. (Reel 1)
    - Associated Producers of Negro Motion Pictures, Frame(s) 240. (Reel 1)
    - Astor Pictures, Frame(s) 241. (Reel 1)
    - Atlantic City, Frame(s) 242. (Reel 1)
    - Attaway, Ruth
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 243-244. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 11-12, Raintree Country 690-692, The President's Lady. (Reel 10)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 382, The Truant. (Reel 12)
    - Attaway, William
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 243, 678. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 451. (Reel 2)
    - Attorney for the Defense, Frame(s) 245, Clarence Muse. (Reel 1)
    - Auf Wiederschen, Frame(s) 246, Louis Armstrong. (Reel 1)
    - Aul, Carmen, Frame(s) 247, La Pacha. (Reel 1)
    - Austin, Jack, Frame(s) 10. (Reel 9)
    - Autobiography of Malcolm X, Frame(s) 250. (Reel 1)
    - Avalos, Ricardo, Frame(s) 352, Katherine Dunham. (Reel 4)
    - Ayers, Benny C., Frame(s) 248. (Reel 1)
    - Ayler, Ethel, Frame(s) 249, Lena Horne. (Reel 1)
  - B
    - Baby Doll, Frame(s) 251, Uncle Pleasant Trotter. (Reel 1)
    - Baby Sister, Frame(s) 252, Chester Himes, Melvin Van Peebles. (Reel 1)
    - Baccus (M.V.) Film Company, Frame(s) 253. (Reel 1)
    - Bachelor Bait, Frame(s) 254, Clarence Wilson. (Reel 1)
    - Bachelor of Arts, Frame(s) 255, Stepin Fetchit. (Reel 1)
    - Bacon, Joe, Frame(s) 256. (Reel 1)
    - Badges, Frame(s) 257. (Reel 1)
    - Badlands, Frame(s) 258-259, Sammy Davis, Jr., & U.S. Prestige. (Reel 1)
    - Bailey, Bill
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 262, Cabin in the Sky 270, Pearl Bailey; 284 drug charge. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 236, Photos. (Reel 2)
    - Bailey, Cal, Frame(s) 263. (Reel 1)
    - Bailey, Pearl
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 264-306. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 311-312, 527, Carmen Jones; Nat King Cole. (Reel 2)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 1-96, Nat King Cole. (Reel 3)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 396-397, Billy Eckstine. (Reel 4)
    - Baily, Thurmond, Frame(s) 502, Negro Entertainers. (Reel 4)
    - Baird, Harry
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 308, Story of a 3-Day Pass & Sapphire. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 57, Harvey Brooks. (Reel 2)
    - Baird, Johnnie, Frame(s) 309, Sapphire. (Reel 1)
    - Baker, George
      See Father Divine
    - Baker, Josephine
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 70, Has troubles; 336-384. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 363, Carol Carter; 431, Japanese sons. (Reel 2)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 207, The Count. (Reel 3)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 629-672. (Reel 4)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 690, Siren of the Tropics. (Reel 11)
    - Baker, LaVerne
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 331-334. (Reel 1)
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 6, Muriel Kahn; 333, Rock, Rock, Rock. (Reel 11)
    - Baker, Sam, Frame(s) 335 *. (Reel 1)
    - Balago, Frame(s) 260, Edmund Low, Oscar Smith. (Reel 1)
    - The Balcony, Frame(s) 261, Ruby Dee. (Reel 1)
    - Baldwin, James
      - unspecified, Frame(s) 132, Another Country; 385-397, 687. (Reel 1)